<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>stellaktran.com</title>
    <description>Hi, I'm Stella Tran. Welcome to my portfolio and website.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 14:21:35 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 14:21:35 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tackling the opioid epidemic</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Addiction impacts over 23M people across the socioeconomic spectrum, but few have access to quality, evidence-based treatment programs. Nearly 19M of people who struggle with addiction go untreated each year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond access, addiction treatment in our healthcare system just isn’t designed for longterm recovery. Our system affords you a 30-day inpatient stay, and, if you’re lucky, you’ll find a good AA program afterward. For those that do receive treatment, the relapse rates were nearly 50%. The outcomes are much poorer for low-income patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, a beast of its own magnitude: opioids. Devastating millions of families and hundreds of communities across the US. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2017/06/05/the-addicts-next-door&quot;&gt;People dropping from overdose in grocery stores and gas stations across the country.&lt;/a&gt; Yet, deep stigma is associated with the gold standard of opioid treatment, and so few providers are available to deliver this care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We looked at several companies looking to drive innovation into the space. Many of the models we found looked to force fit an addiction treatment program into an old, broken payment paradigm, which meant patients still didn’t get the care they needed to successfully recover. Or patients had to self-pay to get a quality program. I had seen enough GoFundMe campaigns, heard enough stories of people taking out second mortgages to fund treatment, and I wanted to see something different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first met with Stephanie Papes, the CEO of Boulder, and then the team soon after, I sensed that they’d build something different. They had a vision for long-term, comprehensive, dignified and patient-centered care, and they wanted to bring opioid addiction treatment to underserved communities in dire need of support. And they deeply understood the system they were building in, and knew where they could push the envelope. This meant finding the right customers and not compromising on the components of care that enabled successful recovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early feedback has come in, and patients &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; Boulder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel so lucky that Acumen is a part of their journey, and that I have the opportunity to watch a CEO and team with such vision and moral leadership. We captured &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/user-894961975/portfolio-podcast-episode-4-boulder-care&quot;&gt;some of this magic in a recent conversation with the CEO&lt;/a&gt;, where we discussed what led her to launch Boulder, despite the payment and regulatory environment, and, most exciting to me, how Boulder is pushing forward a care delivery model and standard of care that may actually work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2019 12:42:31 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tackling-the-opioid-epidemic/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/tackling-the-opioid-epidemic/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Investing in Progress</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Even when the world is burning around you</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/08/06/books/toni-morrison-death.html?module=inline&quot;&gt;Toni Morrison passed away last week&lt;/a&gt;. With the Administration’s hateful rhetoric, and three mass shootings in the span of a week and a half,  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nobelprize.org/prizes/literature/1993/morrison/lecture/?_ga=2.225538394.1593246199.1565612767-1841843972.1565612767&quot;&gt;I found hope in re-visiting her 1993 Nobel Prize speech&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She begins her speech with a story about a wise, blind woman, who is asked by a group of children if a bird that they are holding in their hands is dead or alive. Dead or alive —  the blind woman thinks this is a trick, a cruelty, the fate of this poor creature in the hands of the children. As a part of this story, Morrison uses the bird to illustrate her fear of how language can enable oppression and violence, which feels so timely in our political climate: _“The systematic looting of language can be recognized by the tendency of its users to forgo its nuanced, complex, mid-wifery properties for menace and subjugation. Oppressive language does more than represent violence; it is violence; does more than represent the limits of knowledge; it limits knowledge. Whether it is obscuring state language or the faux-language of mindless media; whether it is the proud but calcified language of the academy or the commodity driven language of science; whether it is the malign language of law-without-ethics, or language designed for the estrangement of minorities, hiding its racist plunder in its literary cheek – it must be rejected, altered and exposed.”&lt;br /&gt;
_&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But alas! The children are ultimately not cruel. They wish to tap into the women’s wisdom and experience to understand life — all of it — and death. I love that Morrison uses the vulnerability of language to build up our own sense of vulnerability for the bird and the power of the children. I can viscerally feel the cruelty, or the anticipation of it, from the children. I imagine the myriad times when I, as I get older, with all my rhyme or reason, look into the eyes of children and feel sheer terror for not knowing what’s behind them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then Morrison quickly reverses our expectations of how the story should go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading this was a reminder of how vulnerability and fear can make it easy to build up walls and false narratives, and I need to fight the desire to judge and close down. Especially during times like this, and even when the world can be so, so ugly. And it was a reminder to have faith that we will have a path toward shared prosperity if we approach these difficult moments without judgement and with openness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Finally”, she says, “I trust you now. I trust you with the bird that is not in your hands because you have truly caught it. Look. How lovely it is, this thing we have done – together.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 11:49:05 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/burning/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/burning/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Shelf Help</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mapping the stages of intimacy to levels of digital security</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m trying to Marie Kondo my digital life, and I’m starting first with messaging apps. tl;dr: It’s really hard to figure out what needs to go. I tried to create a decision framework to help me, and I ultimately ended up with a map that (for the most part) links level of friendship to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.securemessagingapps.com/&quot;&gt;level of security and privacy.&lt;/a&gt; Funny, right? Ok, well, I think it’s funny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reddit DM / Discord:&lt;/strong&gt; Anonymous strangers that know you better than some of the people around you — you are who you want to be, and they are who you need them to be&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Twitter DM:&lt;/strong&gt; Strangers that you may collide with out and about in San Francisco. The more prolific they are, the more it *feels* like you know them. So there you are, the both of you standing in line for ice cream at Bi-Rite, and you say hi only to realize they have no idea who you are. Hi, I’m awkward!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instagram DM:&lt;/strong&gt; Strangers, mostly, and, acquaintances becoming strangers, your relationship held by a delicate thread of responding to each other’s Instagram stories with emojis&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Messenger:&lt;/strong&gt; Acquaintances, mostly. Why do people still use Messenger?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WhatsApp:&lt;/strong&gt; Friends, mostly&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iMessage:&lt;/strong&gt; Friends that have remained friends because you’ve been in the same group thread forever. And Mom, who recently discovered emojis. 🥰💫🎉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Signal:&lt;/strong&gt; Good friends, which include fellow activists, whose connection to you cannot be described in words. Includes friends that have upgraded to better friend status because they think you’re annoying, but like you enough to listen to you preach about Whatsapp metadata, and, uh, Facebook. Also includes your significant other, who you hope will one day respond to your eggplant emoji. He won’t, but you’ll keep trying anyway, and Signal is your best bet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;
  &lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter is-resized&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://stellaktran.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/lol-privacy-825x1024.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-514&quot; width=&quot;483&quot; height=&quot;599&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stellaktran.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/lol-privacy-825x1024.jpg 825w, https://stellaktran.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/lol-privacy-242x300.jpg 242w, https://stellaktran.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/lol-privacy-768x954.jpg 768w, https://stellaktran.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2019/05/lol-privacy.jpg 828w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 483px) 100vw, 483px&quot; /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;Privacy is also more than just encryption. As you design your personal threat model, consider physical risks, which include social engineering. Triple check that you trust the recipient or you could unwittingly become Internet content. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;(Thanks &lt;a href=&quot;https://ryanseys.com&quot;&gt;Ryan&lt;/a&gt; for consenting to my shenanigans!)&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Telegram:&lt;/strong&gt; Best of best friends. You convinced two of them to join during one of your fits about encrypted messaging, privacy, and big Tech. They won’t switch to Signal because they love you enough to not give in to all your demands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, that exercise basically got me nowhere. Back to the whiteboard. For now, I’ll just stick to asking myself what sparks joy as I stare at the 20-30 tabs that I have open at any given time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you’re here, here are a few related reads floating around in my head:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Economist&lt;/strong&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/business/2019/05/02/mark-zuckerberg-wants-to-build-wechat-for-the-west&quot;&gt;Mark Zuckerberg wants to build the West’s WeChat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Viet Tan&lt;/strong&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://viettan.org/en/vcd2019-report/&quot;&gt;Vietnam Cyber Dialogue 3.0&lt;/a&gt;, a brief for a conference that brought activists, policymakers, journalists, and technologists together to discuss Internet censorship in Vietnam, and provides an overview of how Hanoi censors the Internet, and the role of Facebook and other tech firms inadvertently supporting these efforts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jenny Odell&lt;/strong&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/How-Do-Nothing-Resisting-Attention/dp/1612197493&quot;&gt;Resisting the Attention Economy&lt;/a&gt;, and this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.callyourgirlfriend.com/how-to-do-nothing&quot;&gt;great Call Your Girlfriend episode on it&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NYTimes OpEd&lt;/strong&gt; – &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/04/10/opinion/sunday/privacy-capitalism.html?action=click&amp;amp;module=RelatedLinks&amp;amp;pgtype=Article&quot;&gt;How Capitalism Betrayed Privacy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 23:09:38 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/stages-of-intimacy-mapped-to-levels-of-digital-security/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/stages-of-intimacy-mapped-to-levels-of-digital-security/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Annals of Me</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>An ode to unspoken stories</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What are the words you do not yet have? What are the tyrannies you swallow day by day and attempt to make your own, until you will sicken and die of them, still in silence?&lt;/em&gt; – Audre Lorde, &lt;a href=&quot;https://genius.com/Audre-lorde-the-transformation-annotated&quot;&gt;The Transformation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I read this weekend:&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve experienced the power of great storytelling in all of its forms: from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/04/11/magazine/black-mothers-babies-death-maternal-mortality.html&quot;&gt;exceptional&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2014/10/06/before-the-law&quot;&gt;journalism&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Evicted-Poverty-Profit-American-City/dp/0553447459&quot;&gt;that broke my heart and opened my eyes wide&lt;/a&gt;, poetry that spoke intimately to my consciousness, to the chic Glossier ad that sold me the promise of feeling &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.buzzfeed.com/nitashatiku/inside-glossier-the-beauty-startup-that-just-happens-to-sell?utm_term=.xiMxjXw4y#.qbj0aBzgJ&quot;&gt;chic, effortless, and free&lt;/a&gt; when you sport skin as smooth as a baby’s ass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish I could tell good stories. I suck at telling good stories. I never seem to get the pacing right, I don’t give enough context, my punchline is only funny or compelling to me, and I focus in on all the wrong details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suck in part because I’m not practiced. I’ve mostly stayed silent. Perhaps to appear normal, or because of fear and trauma. Or because I didn’t see a space for my stories.  Last weekend, I sat on a panel with a Vietnamese woman that grew up in my neighborhood. In hearing her frank and unsentimental account of her life, I realized that I had never shared my own. With friends, even! I realized that I’m not afraid of vulnerability; I’ve kept silent in fear of being cast as “other”.  And for so long, I’ve adopted versions of stories, allowing other people’s narratives set the bar of what is OK to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It feels comfortable to say storytelling isn’t my jam, shrug it away, and move on with my life. But I need to learn. &lt;strong&gt;My story is so important, and so is yours.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;We further our collective consciousness in deep and meaningful ways when we tell our stories.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do you begin? For me, it starts with getting my stream of consciousness into clear, concise, and digestible writing. I also want to use a variety of tools, including data and strong imagery. Think &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2019/02/21/magazine/minimum-wage-saving-lives.html&quot;&gt;Matthew Desmond&lt;/a&gt;.  Here are the resources I’ve started with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ssir.org/articles/entry/using_story_to_change_systems&quot;&gt;Using Story to Change Systems&lt;/a&gt; (Stanford Social Innovation Review)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://outlier.ai/2017/04/10/data-storytelling/&quot;&gt;How to Use Data Storytelling to Communicate More Effectively&lt;/a&gt; (The Outlier Blog)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.collaborativefund.com/blog/an-art-leveraging-a-science/&quot;&gt;An Art Leveraging Science&lt;/a&gt; (Collaborative Fund)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Writing-Well-Classic-Guide-Nonfiction/dp/0060891548&quot;&gt;On Writing Well by William Zinsser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://newrepublic.com/article/73258/george-orwells-politics-and-english-language-guide-writing&quot;&gt;George Orwell’s Brilliant Guide to Writing Well&lt;/a&gt; (The New Republic)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Rulebook-Arguments-Anthony-Weston/dp/162466654X/ref=pd_lpo_sbs_14_t_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;psc=1&amp;amp;refRID=YER3VD7HV55177BYCXQZ&quot;&gt;A Rulebook for Arguments by Anthony Weston&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 16:39:18 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/an-ode-to-unspoken-stories/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/an-ode-to-unspoken-stories/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Shelf Help</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Interview with Negotiating the Terms</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ember989&quot; class=&quot;ember-view&quot;&gt;I wish &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ember993&quot; class=&quot;tap-target feed-shared-text-view__mention ember-view&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/singareddynm&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-entity-hovercard-id=&quot;urn:li:fs_miniProfile:ACoAABcrb5oBcm85hwqCzNj5eckUXxUR2Q_CQGI&quot;&gt;Nikita Singareddy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ember997&quot; class=&quot;ember-view&quot;&gt;‘s Negotiating the Terms existed when I looked to enter VC. There were few female role models from diverse backgrounds, and I didn’t know of the unique range of career pathways into the industry. NTT is that resource, and I hope it inspires and helps more women enter the industry. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ember997&quot; class=&quot;ember-view&quot;&gt;Even as an investor now, I turn to NTT to see how other women think about our work. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ember997&quot; class=&quot;ember-view&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.negotiatingtheterms.com/blog/stella-tran&quot;&gt;I’m so excited to share my own path to venture capital on Negotiating the Terms.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Who knew that starting a little online shop with &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ember1001&quot; class=&quot;tap-target feed-shared-text-view__mention ember-view&quot; href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ACoAABNg4JIBcbl8ReAAP2Yg841pb17Vq42UHwc/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-entity-hovercard-id=&quot;urn:li:fs_miniProfile:ACoAABNg4JIBcbl8ReAAP2Yg841pb17Vq42UHwc&quot;&gt;Janet Nguyen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;ember1005&quot; class=&quot;ember-view&quot;&gt;in high school would spark my love of (and career in) entrepreneurship and beyond… Big thank you, also, to &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ember1009&quot; class=&quot;tap-target feed-shared-text-view__mention ember-view&quot; href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/6585282/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-entity-hovercard-id=&quot;urn:li:fs_miniCompany:6585282&quot;&gt;Miller Center for Social Entrepreneurship at Santa Clara University&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ember1013&quot; class=&quot;ember-view&quot;&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ember1017&quot; class=&quot;tap-target feed-shared-text-view__mention ember-view&quot; href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/ACoAAAE9QYgB29XSNAKNpQyQidF3Y2EOsRCBt3Y/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-entity-hovercard-id=&quot;urn:li:fs_miniProfile:ACoAAAE9QYgB29XSNAKNpQyQidF3Y2EOsRCBt3Y&quot;&gt;Melissa Richer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;span id=&quot;ember1021&quot; class=&quot;ember-view&quot;&gt;and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;ember1025&quot; class=&quot;tap-target feed-shared-text-view__mention ember-view&quot; href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/company/839324/&quot; target=&quot;_self&quot;&gt;&lt;span data-entity-hovercard-id=&quot;urn:li:fs_miniCompany:839324&quot;&gt;The Ayllu Initiative&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;ember1029&quot; class=&quot;ember-view&quot;&gt;, and more!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally posted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/feed/update/urn:li:activity:6501567756339675137/&quot;&gt;Linkedin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2019 16:21:05 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/interview-with-negotiating-the-terms/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/interview-with-negotiating-the-terms/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Annals of Me</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hidden costs</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I went down a rabbit hole of research to understand &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/article/us-usa-healthcare-diabetes-cost/us-insulin-costs-per-patient-nearly-doubled-from-2012-to-2016-study-idUSKCN1PG136&quot;&gt;the skyrocketing costs of insulin&lt;/a&gt; after &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/01/18/opinion/cost-insurance-diabetes-insulin.html?rref=collection%2Ftimestopic%2FHealth%20Insurance%20and%20Managed%20Care&quot;&gt;reading this op-ed in the New York Times&lt;/a&gt;. Written by Dr. Danielle Ofri, a practicing physician at Bellevue Hospital in New York, she begins the piece by walking through the dizzying experience of managing her patient’s insulin for Type-1 diabetes: near-constant changes on &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; is covered, and &lt;em&gt;how much&lt;/em&gt; is covered. As a result, her patient’s out-of-pockets expenses changed month to month, making it difficult for the patient to budget on a fixed income. This doctor was willing to go above and beyond to work with the pharmacist to figure out what was going on. Sadly, they had little success, and it struck me how few patients have advocates like Dr. Ofri on their end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my research, I felt the same dizzying experience as I navigated the pharma value chain, generics, drug patents, and the system of rebates and coupons that pharma manufacturers, distributors, PBMs and insurers play with to get drugs covered and drive up costs. All of this, at the devastating expense of their patients: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/magazine/wp/2019/01/07/feature/insulin-is-a-lifesaving-drug-but-it-has-become-intolerably-expensive-and-the-consequences-can-be-tragic/?utm_term=.c410ede99c53&quot;&gt;people unable to pay the $1,000+ a month for their medication, people missing doses, people rationing their doses, and the black market, from people donating their doses once a loved one has passed away to people seeking alternative providers beyond our borders&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This research also led me to reflect on a company I recently reviewed. The company wanted to help low-income consumers access drugs at a more affordable cost, and a big piece of its model was using this system of rebates and coupons. That sounds promising at first glance, right? Lowering the cost of drugs means it’s more accessible, and then improved adherence, then improved health outcomes. But maybe not: the story behind insulin was a reminder of how some fixes can cover up the underlying dynamics that created these unjust systems in the first place. And exploiting a loophole (or something broken) here may mean something else must break down in another part of the system. Someone always pays. Sadly, it seems like it’s usually the consumer that has the least power in the system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, related, I’m currently reading Elizabeth Rosenthal’s amazing &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/American-Sickness-Healthcare-Became-Business/dp/1594206759&quot;&gt;An American Sickness&lt;/a&gt;. I don’t know why it took me so long to pick the book up, but I highly recommend if you’re interested in or working in healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:03:06 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/looking-for-hidden-costs/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/looking-for-hidden-costs/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Grounded in Reality</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Operating as if Beijing de facto called the shots</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I read this&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;weekend: &lt;/strong&gt;The Economist has a fairly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/science-and-technology/2019/01/12/can-china-become-a-scientific-superpower&quot;&gt;rosy outlook on China’s ability to lead the world in science and innovation&lt;/a&gt;. An over simplification of their position, but essentially:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Advances in science require collaborating with the international science community, and China will not become the super power that it wants to be if it doesn’t abide by the community’s standards and conventions.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rather than shunning their Chinese counterparts, Western scientists should carefully collaborate such that they can promote accountability and transparency.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At some point, Beijing’s grip on critical thought may hinder their ability to foster innovative thinking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With my own Western bias, this line of reasoning makes a whole lot of sense. I find myself wanting to be as optimistic as the authors. But how does our own biases shape how we right size China’s ability to realize their ambitions? In 2016, China surpassed the U.S. in peer-reviewed science and engineering articles published (although the Economist claims these papers were lower quality). Combined with research coming out of the E.U., the West still leads but China’s growth rate suggests they could catch up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first question I have is perhaps the easiest to answer: what’s the timeline for the West to exert our influence, when Beijing has invested such significant money and brainpower behind the effort?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.static-economist.com/sites/default/files/images/2019/01/articles/body_0&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then: how much soft power do we have, really? Are we preaching to our own? Meanwhile, Beijing has demonstrated its own form of influence in other ways, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/china/2018-08-13/when-china-rules-web?fa_package=1122877&quot;&gt;as it’s tried to do so with the Internet&lt;/a&gt;. And also, &lt;a href=&quot;https://qz.com/1506358/china-got-on-the-bandwagon-to-provide-global-satellite-internet/&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt;. Basically, find other ways to set the rules, and then everyone has to play your game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And are we thinking correctly about capability? Perhaps there are different ways of thinking and reasoning that lead to advances in science, and the West has just demonstrated one way that works. Also, I’d like to think that we all have access to our god-given human ingenuity, and this potential is free from the political system that govern our lives. We shouldn’t let our faith in our capitalist democracy become blind hubris. The Economist speaks a bit to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“But the idea that you can get either truly reliable science or truly great science in a political system that depends on a culture of unappealable authority is, as yet, unproven. Perhaps you can. Perhaps you cannot. And perhaps, in trying to do so, you will discover new ways of thinking as well as fruitful knowledge.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Would it be more prudent if we just operated as if China will become a dominant power in science and technology? We could then be proactive about the potential implications. Meanwhile, we should continue to deliver and set standards for high-quality research. This includes &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/speaking-of-science/wp/2018/08/27/researchers-replicate-just-13-of-21-social-science-experiments-published-in-top-journals/?noredirect=on&amp;amp;utm_term=.a27caa8be3b0&quot;&gt;more transparent and reproducible research&lt;/a&gt;. And finding alternative sources of funding: we frequently fund research through grants &lt;a href=&quot;https://biofortified.org/2018/08/27/conflicts-interest-research-misconduct/&quot;&gt;from organizations that may have a special interest in the outcomes, leading to conflicts of interest and questions the credibility of the outcomes&lt;/a&gt;. And we should invest much more in science and math education.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jan 2019 16:47:13 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/if-beijing-called-the-shots/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/if-beijing-called-the-shots/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Grounded in Reality</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Emergent behaviors</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed this wide ranging conversation between &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/a16z/talent-tech-trends-culture-ben-marc-tyler-cowen-summit-2018&quot;&gt;Marc Andreessen, Ben Horowitz, and Tyler Cowen&lt;/a&gt;, which covers their partnership, how Marc and Ben thought about a16z’s differentiation when they founded the firm, how VC has evolved, and what’s next for [insert your favorite tech or industry here]. There’s several gems in this episode (which somebody painstakingly captured on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.breaker.audio/a16z/e/41740643&quot;&gt;Breaker&lt;/a&gt;) and worth a full listen. Here’s one that I found particularly useful…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Marc, in response to Tyler’s question, “Did you invent the tweet storm?”:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I literally couldn’t shut up, so it sort of catalyzed. The big lesson for these internet platforms is […] &lt;strong&gt;emergent behaviors is incredibly important. The really successful platforms let users surface the behaviors that the creators of the platform could have never thought of.&lt;/strong&gt; Twitter has had issues over the years, but […] the compelling ways people have used Twitter have been invented by users. […] It’s not just Twitter. It was true of the personal computer. It was true of smart phones. It’s been true for many of these Internet platforms. It’s a useful principle for product design: let the users innovate.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emergent behavior extends far beyond product, and is a useful principle across a number of domains. For me, top of mind are community building, advocacy and organizing, but I do wonder how one tracks and responds to these interactions in an offline environment. Y&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 1rem;&quot;&gt;ou’re operating in an environment wherein the data isn’t (1) readily available, and (2) as responsive, so how do you know when that behavior is indicative of a larger group behavior? What is real and what is noise? If you want to co-create with your community, how do you set up a response system for that kind of interaction?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, as a person that’s constantly holding everything in her head, planning everything from A to Z, I appreciate the reminder to let go, enjoy the magic of improvisation, and make it up as I go along (with co-conspirators, if possible).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(P.S. I just realized that my blogs ask a lot of questions but rarely suggests a hypothesis or attempts to find the answer. I’m going to try to do that more in 2019.)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 23:28:05 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/emergent-behaviors/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/emergent-behaviors/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Shelf Help</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A case for optimism</title>
        <description>&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;What I read this weekend: &lt;/strong&gt;I feel such heaviness from the vicious cycle of bad news and bad forecasts, from immigration policy, deteriorating social safety net and world order to climate change and automation. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wycjnCCgUes&quot;&gt;It feels like we&amp;#8217;re only going backward&lt;/a&gt;. And some days, this weight compounds because &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/16/opinion/climate-change-parenting.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.nytimes.com/2018/07/16/opinion/climate-change-parenting.html&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1533806907569000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNHaVxglE8m4dEJdAShit65N4RJhmw&quot;&gt;these problems feel insurmountable&lt;/a&gt;. This &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2018/07/23/bad-news&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2018/07/23/bad-news&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1533806907569000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNGVXTnQYVkE7cdshajZwhH2_orSBg&quot;&gt;Shouts &amp;amp; Murmurs piece&lt;/a&gt; does a great job of capturing the manic hum of doom and gloom.&lt;br class=&quot;m_6729121993356532639gmail-kix-line-break&quot; /&gt;&lt;br class=&quot;m_6729121993356532639gmail-kix-line-break&quot; /&gt;I found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2018/07/23/are-things-getting-better-or-worse&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2018/07/23/are-things-getting-better-or-worse&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1533806907569000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNEZb_no9ndyW_VmIJwlDtw--TBHZQ&quot;&gt;this hopeful article&lt;/a&gt; that makes a case for progress, and in turn, optimism. The author cites Steven Pinker’s Enlightenment Now book and a few other notable thinkers on this topic, and an observation that really stuck with me is that this pessimism could ultimately affect the policies we choose to support and how we vote. I also listened to &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/conversations-with-tyler/vitalik-buterin-tyler-cowen-cryptocurrency-blockchain-tech-3a2b20c12c97&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot; data-saferedirecturl=&quot;https://www.google.com/url?q=https://medium.com/conversations-with-tyler/vitalik-buterin-tyler-cowen-cryptocurrency-blockchain-tech-3a2b20c12c97&amp;amp;source=gmail&amp;amp;ust=1533806907569000&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNFwPigZUG4B612Nz7Z2KwePuswCFg&quot;&gt;an interview with Vitalik Buterin (the founder of Ethereum)&lt;/a&gt;, who believes that the most popular delusion or irrationality should be our belief in progress. I&amp;#8217;m now thinking of ways to actively flip these negative scripts in my head, and to find scripts for hope, optimism, and progress even in trying times. I shared this reflection with my team and some friends, who shared their own awesome life hacks:
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;li dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
  Don&amp;#8217;t get caught up in the minutia of day-to-day news. It&amp;#8217;s OK not to hear every update. Know the key themes.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
  Subscribe to articles about new discoveries and innovations in science.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
  Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gapminder.org/&quot;&gt;Gap Minder,&lt;/a&gt; which provides you with raw data about the world to react to,  rather than hearing about an issue from a news outlet that may have distorted the data to fit a specific narrative. Also, see Outlier&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://outlier.ai/2017/04/10/data-storytelling/&quot;&gt;series on data storytelling&lt;/a&gt;, where the team explores how data can mislead you.
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
  Find and follow people that start from an empty whiteboard to re-design the world, such as Jeremy Rifkin and his thinking around a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.singularityweblog.com/jeremy-rifkin-on-the-zero-marginal-cost-society/&quot;&gt;zero marginal cost society&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Thanks Eliza, Larry, Ryan, and Markeze.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So: what does give me hope? People that show up, as much as they can, like these wonderful humans that came together for the Families Together demonstration. We walked from Dolores Park to Civic Center to protest immigration policy in solidarity with our neighbors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img class=&quot;CToWUd a6T aligncenter&quot; tabindex=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/ZH3lLF7WKPAxBWpHEe9GwcLVovwNSK_NLXYLqVFaYrg8w6Nhxe7b69ZQIceYD5tUgQKZZeMEGtxT9iBsIHjBuDre5SogMSe35QKRvzI6_iuttljlHLtZXR9Ai2oxhzCbT1PeyfLa&quot; width=&quot;420&quot; height=&quot;559&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 02:28:54 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/a-case-for-optimism/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/a-case-for-optimism/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Shelf Help</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Experiencing power</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I just spent an eye-opening ten days in Vietnam, filled with overwhelming amounts of food, tropical fruit, and great conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went in &lt;em&gt;knowing&lt;/em&gt; that Vietnam was one of the fastest growing economies in the world.  And Vietnam’s middle and upper class were enjoying everyday evidence of this, from pizza to craft beer, while new skyscraper developments scattered across Saigon’s skyline. I also knew the other side of the story: one party rule, corruption, repression, and inequality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;But knowing is not as powerful as seeing&lt;/em&gt;, and I found myself startled by the poignant signs of unequal growth. Through out the entire trip, this feeling gnawed at me, and I struggled to articulate the current that ran through my reflections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-301 size-full aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://stellaktran.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/ban-ve-so-1448662296-1448710471-1451904829-1451964263.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;665&quot; height=&quot;443&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stellaktran.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/ban-ve-so-1448662296-1448710471-1451904829-1451964263.jpg 665w, https://stellaktran.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/ban-ve-so-1448662296-1448710471-1451904829-1451964263-300x200.jpg 300w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 665px) 100vw, 665px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found my first clue to make sense of this tension in re-reading Barack Obama’s extraordinary &lt;em&gt;Dreams from My Father&lt;/em&gt;. He writes of his Indonesian stepfather’s sudden change in disposition when the family moved to Indonesia (bolded emphasis my own):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;_“Power. _The word fixed in my mother’s mind like a curse. &lt;strong&gt;In America, it had generally remained hidden from view until you dug beneath the surface of things&lt;/strong&gt;; until you visited an Indian reservation or spoke to a black person whose trust you had earned. &lt;strong&gt;But here power was undisguised, indiscriminate, naked, always fresh in memory.&lt;/strong&gt; Power had taken Lolo and yanked him back in line just when he thought he’d escape, &lt;strong&gt;making him feel its weight, letting him know that his life wasn’t his own&lt;/strong&gt;. That’s how things were; you couldn’t change it, you could just live by the rules, so simple once you learned them. And so Lolo had made his peace with power, learned the wisdom of forgetting…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m flooded with reactions, but I’ll let this clue (and the others I’m finding) marinate for now and report back. Hold me accountable to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some contextual reads, if you’re interested:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloomberg.com/view/articles/2018-05-23/vietnam-is-a-frontier-market-for-good-reason&quot;&gt;Vietnam is a Frontier Market for Good Reason&lt;/a&gt; (Bloomberg)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oxfam.org/sites/www.oxfam.org/files/file_attachments/bp-vietnam-inequality-120117-en.pdf&quot;&gt;Even it Up: How to Tackle Inequality in Vietnam&lt;/a&gt; (Oxfam International)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldbank.org/vi/news/feature/2014/07/08/inequality-in-vietnam-a-special-focus-of-the-taking-stock-report-july-2014&quot;&gt;Trọng tâm đặc biệt về bất bình đẳng ở Việt Nam&lt;/a&gt; (World Bank)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And a few current-ish events to know:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.techinasia.com/talk/vietnam-under-microscope-prospects-startup-future&quot;&gt;Vietnam under the microscope: Its prospects for a startup future&lt;/a&gt; (Tech in Asia)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vietcetera.com/blockchain-technology-in-vietnam-becoming-a-global-leader/&quot;&gt;Blockchain Technology in Vietnam: Becoming a Global Leader?&lt;/a&gt; (Vietcetera)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rfa.org/english/multimedia/timeline/VnDissident.html&quot;&gt;Timeline of Vietnam’s Dissident Crackdown&lt;/a&gt; (Radio Free Asia)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.loa.fm/our-stories/april-2018-trial&quot;&gt;Six Vietnamese Activists Sentenced to Sixty Six Years in Prison&lt;/a&gt; (Loa)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amnesty.org/en/latest/news/2018/06/viet-nam-cybersecurity-law-devastating-blow-freedom-of-expression/&quot;&gt;New Cybersecurity law a devastating blow for freedom of expression&lt;/a&gt; (Amnesty International)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/experiencing-power/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/experiencing-power/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Book Notes</category>
        
        <category>Grounded in Reality</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Informal (and inclusive) economies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In April, I spoke at &lt;a href=&quot;http://utopia.do/&quot;&gt;Utopia’s&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/utopia-studio-warming-who-controls-the-future-of-our-cities-tickets-43154297666#&quot;&gt;San Francisco studio opening.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Utopia is an urban design and innovation firm that looks to re-imagine &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.citylab.com/equity/2017/10/should-we-retire-the-word-slum/542415/&quot;&gt;slums&lt;/a&gt;, and to develop tools to help people design their own city. A group of us were asked to speak about considerations in city design and beyond, and we had the opportunity to openly interpret this prompt:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Barry Pousman&lt;/strong&gt; (Institute for the Future) shared the narrative power of VR to start movements and raise philanthropy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Karen Mok (&lt;/strong&gt;Citizens Advisory Council of the SF Grants for the Arts) talked about the frictions in public arts funding, and why it’s important to invest in a vibrant arts community and cultural policy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lance Cassidy&lt;/strong&gt; (DXLabs, Singularity U) shared his work at DXLabs, and how they’re enabling people and companies to consider and design for the distant future&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shared something very close to my heart: &lt;strong&gt;my community in San Jose.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-313 aligncenter&quot; style=&quot;font-size: 1rem;&quot; src=&quot;https://stellaktran.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-13-at-7.25.06-PM-1024x576.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;739&quot; height=&quot;416&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stellaktran.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-13-at-7.25.06-PM-1024x576.png 1024w, https://stellaktran.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-13-at-7.25.06-PM-300x169.png 300w, https://stellaktran.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-13-at-7.25.06-PM-768x432.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 739px) 100vw, 739px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;em&gt;Slide from my talk: my favorite tofu house in San Jose, with prices that have not risen to match inflation or the rising cost of living in the Bay Area&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 1rem;&quot;&gt;Like other refugees that immigrated to the United States after the Vietnam war, my parents didn’t have much when they arrived. They slowly built a life for themselves and their families, and I credit much of this to our community and the informal economy we created to make ends meet. What does that mean? Rather than transact in cold hard cash, we traded in goodwill and services. Together, we bootstrapped toward a more tolerable quality of life. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-315&quot; src=&quot;https://stellaktran.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-13-at-8.01.34-PM-1024x577.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;739&quot; height=&quot;416&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stellaktran.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-13-at-8.01.34-PM-1024x577.png 1024w, https://stellaktran.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-13-at-8.01.34-PM-300x169.png 300w, https://stellaktran.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-13-at-8.01.34-PM-768x433.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 739px) 100vw, 739px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like: when I hit someone’s car, and the local mechanic basically fixed that car for free because my mom helped his son find a job. I was fresh out of college, and I would’ve otherwise wiped out my savings. I’m not unique: 44% of Americans are unable to cover a $400 emergency expense out of pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-large wp-image-314 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://stellaktran.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-13-at-7.25.20-PM-1024x575.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;739&quot; height=&quot;415&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stellaktran.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-13-at-7.25.20-PM-1024x575.png 1024w, https://stellaktran.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-13-at-7.25.20-PM-300x168.png 300w, https://stellaktran.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-13-at-7.25.20-PM-768x431.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 739px) 100vw, 739px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like: when my uncle–a doctor in the community–gives free health advice. In return, his patients share what they can. We get the sweetest, most mouthwatering oranges from one of his patients.  This is so compelling when you compare it against the exorbitant cost of being healthy and well in our country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Certainly, the informal economy also allows for bad actors. You don’t have to look hard to find the hundreds of vulnerable domestic workers that are unseen by the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in the best way, our informal economy acted as a de-facto social safety net that &lt;em&gt;we, the people,&lt;/em&gt; built. A safety net of our own design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-large wp-image-316&quot; src=&quot;https://stellaktran.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-13-at-7.24.44-PM-1024x576.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;739&quot; height=&quot;416&quot; srcset=&quot;https://stellaktran.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-13-at-7.24.44-PM-1024x576.png 1024w, https://stellaktran.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-13-at-7.24.44-PM-300x169.png 300w, https://stellaktran.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2018/06/Screen-Shot-2018-06-13-at-7.24.44-PM-768x432.png 768w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 739px) 100vw, 739px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So my case to the room:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How might we consider the informal economy in our design, while providing the necessary social protections?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do we create space and policy that reflect and enhance dynamics of these arrangements?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 May 2018 19:23:56 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/informal-economy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/informal-economy/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Grounded in Reality</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Eat your vegetables: a reflection on meditation</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve never met a vegetable that I didn’t like, and I credit this to the magic of Vietnamese cuisine and my mother’s cooking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She grew up in the cooking traditions of Huế, the former imperial capital of Vietnam. To accommodate royalty, its people had a fierce devotion to perfectionism, and you can see this conscious attention to quality in every part of its culture. When I think of food from Central Vietnam, I think of dishes that are focused on nuance and the details, with a particular gift for illuminating the flavor profile of vegetables. Take my mom’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/B%C3%BAn_b%C3%B2_Hu%E1%BA%BF&quot;&gt;bún bò Huế (Huế-style beef noodle soup)&lt;/a&gt; for example: you blanche a mixture of raw bean sprouts, mint, basil, banana flower in a steaming bowl of 12-hour lemongrass and beef broth. Vegetables were/are dank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember reading books and watching Disney channel shows about American families, and was struck by how much other kids seemed to hate vegetables. Vegetables were a dramatic point of contention between kids and their parents, and I remember lying to my friends about hating broccoli to fit in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this to say, my relationship with what is good and healthy for my mind, body, and soul started off easy. And this became my experience with self-care: mostly easy. There was nothing a good run, a face mask, or treating myself couldn’t fix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;but-sometimes-the-things-that-are-good-for-you-can-be-difficult-and-unpleasant&quot;&gt;But sometimes, the things that are good for you can be difficult and unpleasant&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I joined venture capital a few years ago, and I wish I could say it’s been smooth sailing. I feel like I’m continually battling the decision fatigue and emotional roller coaster of (1) making (many) sound decisions and (2) being thoughtful about how to best support and empower entrepreneurs. And day after day of this stress and anxiety, I found it harder to recover. Things that used to get me back to baseline–like say, the sheer physical exhaustion from a run that gives you that incredible runner’s high–no longer worked. Nursing running injuries, I feared what would happen if I could no longer run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, I didn’t even realize I was burning out until I discovered &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/schlaf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Steve Shlafman&lt;/a&gt;’s blog on his &lt;a href=&quot;https://schlaf.me/2017/09/25/10-days-of-silence-for-a-lifetime-of-wisdom/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;experience of a 10-day Goenka Vipassana meditation retreat&lt;/a&gt;. He writes (emphasis mine): “I was healing myself by focusing on and accepting these physical pains that I’ve been afraid of for more than a decade. Instead of running, I had no choice but to surrender and in many ways kill my ego. […] &lt;strong&gt;In some ways, I felt like performed surgery on my mind and body. It was a surreal and deeply moving experience.&lt;/strong&gt; Thankfully, I was able to face some deeply rooted and underlying issues that had been bothering me for nearly two decades.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something clicked. I craved that mental clarity and peace, to re-orient the neurons in my brain that fired in all directions. &lt;strong&gt;I recognized that I had to learn new models of self-care or else I’d truly burn out.&lt;/strong&gt; And so I texted my friend &lt;a href=&quot;https://ryanseys.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Ryan Seys&lt;/a&gt; a link to Steve’s blog and asked him to embark on a 30-Day Meditation Challenge with me, and hold me accountable to learning how to be healthy and well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It wasn’t easy. It still isn’t.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;But here I am, four months later, with a daily practice, to say: &lt;strong&gt;thank goodness for meditation.&lt;/strong&gt; If you’re craving that clarity and peace and haven’t started, I hope you do. Here’s my hot take for you, in case something clicks to help you get started: three tips to start your practice today, three tips to sustain your practice, and three takeaways. Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tips-on-starting&quot;&gt;Tips on starting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t start your meditation practice on a Monday.&lt;/strong&gt; Do you ever find yourself daydreaming about the new person you’ll become on Monday? Or after your birthday, next month, or after the New Year? We use these arbitrary benchmarks based on our time biases, but &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcompany.com/3048414/why-thursday-is-the-best-day-to-start-a-new-habit&quot;&gt;data shows that those are the worst days to start new habits.&lt;/a&gt; I always tried to start on Monday, and so I never picked it up. &lt;strong&gt;My tip for you: just start. &lt;/strong&gt;Don’t wait for the perfect day, because it likely won’t happen. &lt;em&gt;And don’t wait to try when you’re already feeling uneasy or anxious.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start small, but it may take longer sessions to find your groove.&lt;/strong&gt; Don’t let the folks on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/meditation&quot;&gt;/r/meditation&lt;/a&gt; that finish hour long meditations and have out-of-body experiences scare you from trying. Try it right now: set a timer for 2 minutes. Inhale for one second, exhale for two, rinse and repeat. Congratulations, you just started! You may not feel anything, but that’s OK. I tried a few times to start before my 30-Day Challenge, and I’d quit because I didn’t feel anything after a 5-minute meditation. After forcing myself to sit through 10-30 minute meditations for 30 days, I found my breakthrough moment at 25 minutes. But it can be intimidating to start your practice by sitting with yourself for that long, so start small and build up.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find an accountability partner.&lt;/strong&gt; Find someone that will &lt;em&gt;actually&lt;/em&gt; call you up and call you out. It helps if that person is committed to learning as much as you. Ryan and I kept a meditation log, which you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1o5I_1SWdLr6wiFivMthrvGlukpiw6C_cun_YB3DptkQ/edit?usp=sharing&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;make a copy of&lt;/a&gt; and use with your partner. We also journaled about our experience, which allowed us to talk through some of the questions we had. See below for tips on sustaining. I also kept a version of this log with my friends &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/radha_mistry&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Radha&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://charlotte-parker.squarespace.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Charlotte&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tips-on-sustaining&quot;&gt;Tips on sustaining&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commit to trying.&lt;/strong&gt; In the beginning, it didn’t feel like anything was happening, and I felt &lt;em&gt;so&lt;/em&gt; uncomfortable without a framework for how it should work. Am I doing this right? How am I supposed to be breathing? Why do I breathe so weird? What is my mind supposed to do? Is it supposed to do &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt;? Don’t worry, that’s normal. It helped that Ryan and I had our daily journal to compare notes. According to our logs, Ryan had his breakthrough on Day 18. For me, it took until Day 22. And when you first start, getting into the habit is more important than getting it right.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Acknowledge potential distractions, and set intentions.&lt;/strong&gt; In my early meditations, I would suddenly remember that I had to add something to my task list and would fixate on it. I would also fixate on the deeper, less fun stuff that I’d rather not share on the Internet. I found that setting a 5 minute timer to write it all down, to verbalize to myself that I had acknowledged it and that I was committed to meditating for the sake of my health and wellbeing, helped make the meditation smoother.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If it’s not working, try other ways.&lt;/strong&gt; During my experience, I switched between Headspace, Meditation Studio, setting a timer, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hvOgpzRJxJg&quot;&gt;several&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VTXIG3ZQgVk&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ERlU8ZS7KfU&amp;amp;t=151s&quot;&gt;videos&lt;/a&gt;. Before my challenge, I’d quit because I thought Andy (from Headspace) had the most annoying voice in the entire universe. Funny enough, I now use Headspace (in combination with other things, as needed) and adore Andy, but trying different things allowed me to find something that worked.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;learnings&quot;&gt;Learnings&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yielding to the present:&lt;/strong&gt; In reflection, I learned that I have two modes of operating: (1) rehashing the past, and giving it a narrative, or (2) rehearsing the future. It’s great to reflect and be thoughtful, but not to the point where you no longer live in the present. Slowly following each rise and fall of my breath taught me how to be singularly focused on the present. Most powerfully, I learned that it can be unproductive to rehash and rehearse. Often the past and future are out of your control, and the only thing you can impact is what’s happening right now.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shifting gears from multi-tasking to deliberate action.&lt;/strong&gt; Do you have moments in your life where you do just one thing? Probably few. If you’re like me, you probably didn’t make it this far because you’re reading the other tab open in your browser. I’ve recognized that multi-tasking doesn’t work, but couldn’t shake off years of this learned behavior. In meditation, the act of doing nothing but sitting with myself, as well as  mentally shifting my attention back to my breath every time I was distracted, was the ultimate forcing function to break from this habit. But multi-tasking is an addiction, and so meditation is a daily reminder to slow down and be more deliberate.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What you feel isn’t (always) real.&lt;/strong&gt; I like to break down everything I feel, and to look at it from many different angles. Before meditation, I found peace in being able to assign narrative to my feelings, and this gave my life order and structure. In the course of watching the myriad thoughts that rushed through my brain for 10-30 minutes, I learned that much of what I feel is fleeting, and I have the ability to let emotions pass. This has been the greatest gift to manage (the volume of) stress: instead of mulling over each new feeling that pops up in my brain, I kind of let it hang for awhile, and see how it flows. &lt;strong&gt;And I developed a bias towards action, rather than dwelling. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And lastly, my experience with meditation is, and continues to be, so much more about the journey than arriving at some final state where I’m more resilient, happier, and healthier. The journey hasn’t been easy, at times unpleasant, but it’s the ultimate act of self-care that I’ve learned. Eat your vegetables, kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next step: tackling sleep + sleep hygiene. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Special thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;https://ryanseys.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Ryan&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/radha_mistry&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Radha&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://charlotte-parker.squarespace.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Charlotte&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/schlaf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;Steve&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You can also read about Ryan’s experience &lt;a href=&quot;https://ryanseys.com/post/breathing&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noopener&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 04:01:06 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/eat-your-vegetables/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/eat-your-vegetables/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Annals of Me</category>
        
        <category>Shelf Help</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Xi Jinping&amp;#8217;s impact on Asia Pacific and beyond</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What I’m reading this weekend:&lt;/strong&gt; At the end of February, the Chinese Community Party abolished the two-term limit for the presidency, effectively allowing President Xi Jinping to lead China in perpetuity. It always seemed to me (read: my untrained eye) that autocrats took incremental, almost unnoticeable actions to amass power, as to not raise any alarms and to sustain the pretense that they rule at the will of their people. China’s monumental decision to amend their constitution may be another sign that &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/the-rise-of-the-worlds-new-emperors-with-americas-help&quot;&gt;today’s autocrats are feeling more emboldened&lt;/a&gt;, and Xi joins the list of authoritarian strongmen taking bold moves— tangible and symbolic—to grab and sustain their power. Why does this matter? For a number of reasons, but here’s one: at the end of the seesaw sits human rights and civil liberties. I recall a conversation with a group of activists shortly after Trump’s election, who predicted that internal discord within the United States would pull attention and resources from issues abroad and create a vacuum for bad political behavior*. As a result, it could meaningfully unwind the work that activists around the world had done to fight inequality, and curtail social and political repression. And so it goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been following the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/04/world/asia/carl-vinson-vietnam.html&quot;&gt;tensions in the South China Sea&lt;/a&gt;, with a particular interest in how &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/news/asia/21731192-american-indifference-has-contributed-crackdown-dissidents-communist-party?zid=306&amp;amp;ah=1b164dbd43b0cb27ba0d4c3b12a5e227&quot;&gt;Vietnam is navigating these dynamics&lt;/a&gt;, and looked to understand how Xi Jinping’s unyielding power would affect the region (and beyond). If you’re interested, here’s a hodgepodge of content that I came across this week, providing both good context and commentary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ft.com/content/0619863a-7e72-4b38-9d71-151d3cd22d6d&quot;&gt;China discards model of fixed-term presidency&lt;/a&gt; (FT Podcast)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/26/world/asia/xi-jinping-career-highlights.html&quot;&gt;President Xi Jinping’s Rise in China&lt;/a&gt; (New York Times)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/03/04/world/europe/europe-china-xi-trump-trade.html&quot;&gt;Europe Once Saw Xi Jinping as a Hedge Against Trump&lt;/a&gt; (New York Times)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.economist.com/news/china/21737543-unhappiness-china-palpable-xi-jinping-decides-abolish-presidential-term-limits&quot;&gt;Xi Jinping decides to abolish presidential term limits&lt;/a&gt; (The Economist)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/xi-jinping-and-the-perils-of-one-person-rule-in-china&quot;&gt;Xi Jinping and the Perils of One-Person Rule in China&lt;/a&gt; (New Yorker)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;font-size: 1rem;&quot; href=&quot;http://foreignpolicy.com/2018/02/26/globalization-has-created-a-chinese-monster/&quot;&gt;Globalization Has Created a Chinese Monster&lt;/a&gt; (Foreign Policy)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/china/2018-03-02/counterproductive-cold-war-china?cid=int-lea&amp;amp;pgtype=hpg&quot;&gt;A Counterproductive Cold War With China&lt;/a&gt; (Foreign Affairs)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.foreignaffairs.com/articles/china/2018-02-13/life-chinas-asia?cid=int-lea&amp;amp;pgtype=hpg&quot;&gt;Life in China’s Asia – What Regional Hegemony Would Look Like&lt;/a&gt; (Foreign Affairs)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;* This is not to say that the U.S. doesn’t act badly, but that’s another conversation for another day.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 19:33:47 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/xi-jinpings-impact-on-asia-pacific-and-beyond/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/xi-jinpings-impact-on-asia-pacific-and-beyond/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Grounded in Reality</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>To see without my eyes</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Huh. I can’t believe it’s already March. If this is any indication of how the rest of the year will unfold…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, here’s a playlist I made that dampens any unease I feel as I stare into the abyss of 2018. It has some sludgey lo-fi, opera, new age chill meets electronica banger, a delicate Trịnh Công Sơn track sung by Khánh Ly, that still feels fresh off vinyl—all inspired by Sufjan Steven’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://consequenceofsound.net/2017/11/sufjan-stevens-shares-stirring-score-for-coming-of-age-drama-call-me-by-your-name-stream-download/&quot;&gt;devastatingly beautiful score for Call Me By Your Name.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
  &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vulture did a fun profile of &lt;a href=&quot;http://&amp;lt;a href=&quot;&gt;Sufjan Steven and his collaboration with director Luca Guadagnino&lt;/a&gt;, which included several golden nuggets on their creative process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To share two that stuck with me…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The magic of sharing sensibilities, or sharing how you intimately process and communicate the various textures of being alive:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Luca’s a real sensualist, and I very quickly keyed into that because I am, as well […] There’s a physicality to his work that’s really profound, and there’s an emotional experience that’s occurring as well, and they have this divine interaction. So that’s really what I was working on, this idea of first love being really irrational and sensational, and feeling boundless in its experience.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the state of flow behind the magic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I firmly believe in the power of impulse and instinct, and the ideology of ‘first thought, best thought,’ […] I have to admit that often when I’m writing music, I’m sort of at a loss for how it all transpires. It feels so immediate and impulsive that I feel like I’m almost not in control. I’m not writing in a state of ecstasy, per se, but I feel almost powerless to the creative motion.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope you’ll take a chance on the playlist, and may you find flow, people, and work that speak to your consciousness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Also, I make a lot of these things. &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/user/122333622?si=iPHqI3zMR1K6gp2vduOV3w&quot;&gt;Follow me on Spotify&lt;/a&gt;!)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 21:59:18 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/to-see-without-my-eyes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/to-see-without-my-eyes/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Tones &amp;amp; Textures</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Finding hope in the next frontier</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, everyone’s favorite billionaire bro genius slash Internet cult leader pushed the bounds of possibility and our imagination, and launched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/science/live/2018/feb/06/spacex-falcon-heavy-launch-elon-musk-live-updates&quot;&gt;the world’s most powerful rocket into space&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I sit here and drill &lt;a href=&quot;https://spaceflightnow.com/2018/02/15/photos-spacexs-imagery-of-falcon-heavy-test-flight/&quot;&gt;these images into my memory&lt;/a&gt;, I think of a conversation I had with a remarkable entrepreneur looking to refuel satellites. He had this insatiable desire to tackle the next frontier, grounded in a vision that exploring space would be such a grand endeavor that it’d unite humanity. I was also struck by his vision of the near-term impact: “What if this could be the next industrial revolution? What if we could bridge developing economies to the next revolution by helping them invest in systems and infrastructure to manufacture these large scale projects?” I immediately thought of the new opportunity for skilled work in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Refueling satellites. Big idea. Creating more harmonious, symbiotic systems. Bigger idea. Sure, there are several ways you could find fallacy in that line of thought, but it’s not every day Elon sends a Tesla to space. Let’s suspend judgement for a second, ponder the possibilities, and dream big.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. If you’re reading this blog and you happen to be an impact investor looking for new ideas, take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spaceangels.com/&quot;&gt;Space Angels&lt;/a&gt; and peep their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.spaceangels.com/portfolio&quot;&gt;portfolio&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2018 18:06:09 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/finding-hope-in-the-next-frontier/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/finding-hope-in-the-next-frontier/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Wild Dreams</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Beyond our borders: what&amp;#8217;s our responsibility?</title>
        <description>&lt;p id=&quot;audioplayer_9433&quot;&gt;
  &lt;audio controls=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;source src=&quot;http://370rock.co/wp-content/uploads/2017/11/SiR_Something_Foreign_ft_ScHoolboy_Q_370rock.co.mp3&quot; type=&quot;audio/mpeg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/audio&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 1rem;&quot;&gt;SiR— Something Foreign ft. ScHoolboy Q&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s devastating that the Trump Administration is ending &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/01/08/us/salvadorans-tps-end.html?&quot;&gt;Temporary Protected Status for the 200,000 people who migrated to the U.S. after the 2001 earthquakes in El Salvador&lt;/a&gt;.  These Salvadorans must now leave the home they’ve known for nearly two decades, where they’ve had families, developed community ties, and contributed to our economy by working, starting small businesses, and paying taxes. As I woke up to the announcement this morning, I was reminded of the half-baked foreign and immigration policies between the U.S. and El Salvador in the 80s/90s—and the longstanding impact these policies have had on our country and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first wave of Salvadorans entered the U.S. in the early 80s, seeking asylum from the Civil War between the military-led government and left-wing guerillas. This was a war that the United States actively supported via monetary and military aid to a government that committed scores of human rights offenses to stay in power. In its post-war report, the U.N. found that “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thenation.com/article/time-for-a-us-apology-to-el-salvador/&quot;&gt;more than 85 percent of the killings, kidnappings, and torture had been the work of government forces, which included paramilitaries, death squads, and army units trained by the United States&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many asylum seekers settled in Los Angeles, where they encountered the poverty of South Central and brutality of Black and Mexican street gangs. In response, Salvadorans banded together to form the violent MS-13 and Barrio 18. Against the backdrop of race-related gang violence was also the beginning of the Crack Epidemic, and Los Angeles saw a 50% increase in gang-related homicides during this time. Gang members began filling up California prisons, and non-US citizens were deported back to their home country.  For Salvadorans, El Salvador had just signed the Peace Treaty in 1992. The country was still rebuilding itself after the war. Without the infrastructure to support these deportees, the gang members of South Central returned to continue their reign of violence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This violence still &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2017/01/23/the-deportees-taking-our-calls&quot;&gt;continues to plague the country today&lt;/a&gt;. San Salvador is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2016/11/21/world/americas/el-salvador-drugs-gang-ms-13.html?&quot;&gt;one of the most dangerous cities in the world&lt;/a&gt;, where, in lieu of other opportunities, gang members rely on extortion and violence to &lt;em&gt;make ends meet&lt;/em&gt;. Returning to El Salvador could be &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2018/01/15/when-deportation-is-a-death-sentence&quot;&gt;a death sentence&lt;/a&gt; for Salvadorans on the Temporary Protected Status. It’s also unlikely El Salvador will have the infrastructure to support this large influx of people. That’s 200,000 re-entering a small country of 6.4 million people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 1rem;&quot;&gt;When I shared the news with a friend, he responded: “Well, it’s a temporary protection. It’s not like they can stay here forever. What’s our responsibility?” In an imaginary world where the impact and consequences of our actions are neatly confined to our corner of the universe, and our corner only—um, sure, &lt;em&gt;maybe.&lt;/em&gt; We wipe our hands clean and call it a day. However, with El Salvador, there is a very clear link between our actions and policies and what El Salvador looks like today. &lt;em&gt;We are very much responsible.&lt;/em&gt; And today, our country chooses &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em style=&quot;font-size: 1rem;&quot;&gt;again&lt;/em&gt; &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 1rem;&quot;&gt;to enact haphazard policies that may have irrevocable, devastating impact on Salvadoran communities here and abroad. &lt;em&gt;And we are also responsible for what happens next.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of El Salvador, the events are a bit more linear, closer to home, the timeline is shorter, and the impact is tangible. We’re afforded a tighter aperture to judge our actions, and it’s easier to connect the dots if you have the facts and do a little digging. That’s not always the case in other situations, and our complicated history is riddled with secrets and sins. Like say, compared to trying to comprehend what happened/is happening in Syria and the Middle East (but hey, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Fractured-Lands-Arab-World-Apart/dp/0525434437&quot;&gt;this is a good start&lt;/a&gt; if you’re interested). It’s hard to sit down and parse out the nuance. Personally for me and my little pea brain, I often can’t find the mental space or emotional energy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what if, instead, we broke away from the minutia of figuring out who’s responsible for what and whom? What if we just flipped our mental model of how we should interact with the world beyond our borders? Start with: it’s &lt;em&gt;always our responsibility&lt;/em&gt;. There are no borders. (Quick aside: being borderless could be our country’s ultimate reparation.) Let’s start from a blank slate on how the world could look. Perhaps then, we can begin thinking creatively about what comes next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very hopeful that what comes next is a more prosperous, inclusive world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 01:20:30 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/whats-our-responsibility/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/whats-our-responsibility/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Grounded in Reality</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Coping mechanisms</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey, world!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s my first blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To celebrate, I’d like to share my favorite (possibly counterfeit) comic from Calvin and Hobbes. I revisit this comic every time I have a panic attack about sharing too much of my data and contributing to the inevitable AI takeover. (All this said as I purr sweet nothings into my Google Home.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;wp-image-15 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;http://stellaktran.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/161e3106f8f1e5963c832775db065148-calvin-and-hobbes-quotes-kid-stuff.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;257&quot; height=&quot;354&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; doing? Why are you reading this? &lt;em&gt;Go play already&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 19:50:21 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/coping-mechanisms/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/coping-mechanisms/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Annals of Me</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
